

LORELEI CRETU

PRODUCT MANAGER

CONTACT

WWW.LORELEICRETU.COM

EDUCATION

B.A. COMMUNICATIONS
Arizona State University
2004 - 2008

B.S. INTERNATIONAL STUDIES
Arizona State University
2004 - 2008

TRAINING

Intro to Marketing
Wharton (Coursera)

Business MetricsDuke University (Coursera)

Learn SQL (CodeCademy)

SQL: Table Transformation (CodeCademy)

SQL: Business Metrics (CodeCademy)

Product DesignGoogle (Udacity)

UX Master Course (Udemy)

Project Management (PMP class)

ABOUT

From a startup to working at one of the top 10 U.S. media companies, have acquired over 13 years of experience in product, project and content management, as well as business analysis and web design.

Believe that a great product lies at the intersection of users' needs and a relentless team.

EXPERIENCE

PRODUCT MANAGER

GANNETT | 2014 - PRESENT

- Work with key business stakeholders to define product strategy, requirements, user stories and KPIs; prioritize sprint backlog and optimize roadmap; track and report product performance metrics, trends and competition; and maintain clear communication while leading distributed design and engineering teams to ensure we deliver quality features on time
- Launched more than a dozen B2C and internal products that aligned with company's strategic goals, generated nearly \$10M in revenue, reached new users, and garnered press attention
- Founded internal program to foster innovation that allows product, project managers, designers and developers to dedicate up to 20% of their time on creative solutions and learn new skills
- Revamped JIRA workflow and led training for entire division to maximize efficiency across multiple remote teams and make it easier to onboard new hires, interns
- As a product and project manager led team that created a custom content management system to support nearly 20 markets for local Ted-like storytelling events and the best local businesses
- Spearheaded efforts in creating a SQL mapping tool that resulted in company-wide database restructuring initiative and new data validation methods to ensure accurate API feed imports

SR. DIGITAL MANAGER

AZCENTRAL.COM | 2012-2014

- Managed team of 9 producers and interns for the Entertainment, Lifestyle and Travel sections of azcentral.com, as well as oversaw planning, content strategy and mentored new hires
- Generated content based on Omniture analytics reports and advised editors and reporters on how to create content based on their individual performance metrics
- Was product owner for the creation and enhancements of two different content management systems, and co-managed rollout for a third CMS
- Created materials and organized training for over 200 employees for fourth CMS
- Product owner for updates to former azcentral.com native apps (iOS, Android, iPad) that increased traffic by 17% within a week
- Led digital initiatives and content strategy that resulted in a 30% yearover-year growth
- Implemented SEO techniques that increased traffic by 55%

AWARDS & HONORS

GANNETT Creative problem solving Winner, 2016

> Innovation Finalist, 2012 + 2013

Leadership Development 2013

AZCENTRAL.COM Employee of the year 2012 + 2013

INTERESTS

Traveling, kickboxing, dancing, novels, superhero movies, tinkering with gadgets and software, always learning, pets, photography, music, and fashion.

CAN'T LIVE WITHOUT

My iPhone, Kindle, Google.com, and french press.

MULTI-LINGUAL English, Romanian, Spanish, Italian

DIGITAL PRODUCER

AZCENTRAL.COM | 2008-2012

- Produced content and managed the Entertainment & Lifestyle social media accounts of the media company, increasing followers by 70%
- Created content tool that increased azcentral.com traffic by 35%
- Assigned interns and freelancers weekly photo assignments and reached out directly to local public relations firms for photos that led to 24% in budget savings
- Coordinated media coverage for "X-Men Origins: Wolverine" world premiere in Tempe, "So You Think You Can Dance" Phoenix auditions and "American Idol" Phoenix auditions

EVENT COORDINATOR

LIVING SOCIAL | 2011

WEB DESIGNER

FREELANCER | 2007 - 2008

WEB DESIGNER

DSI/SEGWAY OF PHOENIX | 2004-2008

- Redesigned and maintained the e-commerce and corporate websites of the manufacturing startup company
- Managed Google Analytics reports, AdWords campaigns and SEO Wrote and edited product copy, instructions and press releases for its OEM/ODM products
- Designed marketing collateral such as ads, brochures, logos, blog graphics, posters, packaging
- Handled eBay, Amazon Marketplace e-commerce stores sales and customer support
- Helped organize Segway of Phoenix promotional events such as Arizona Cardinals football players racetrack event and Segway tours at the J.W. Marriott Hotel in Scottsdale

SKILLS & TOOLS

- Product/ project management: JIRA (used Agile Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall), Basecamp, Trello
- Product requirements: Confluence, Google Docs, MS Office
- Product roadmap: Roadmunk
- UI/ UX design: Balsamiq, Sketch, Photoshop, Invision
- Analytics: Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics, Domo, AppAnnie
- User research: Typeform, SurveyMonkey, Formstack, Polldaddy
- HTML/ CSS: Atom, Dreamweaver
- Code management: Github
- Mindmapping: Popplet
- A/B testing: Optimizely
- Newsletter management, testing: Salesforce Marketing Cloud, Litmus
- Communication: Slack, Skype for Business, Google Hangouts, Zoom, Join.me, UberConference